SUMMARY

Driven Front End Developer well versed in Drupal and scrum team collaborations to formulate + conceptualize corporate web presence. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS, Drupal and JavaScript ensuring websites meet highest standards for best practices, web accessibility, responsive web design and user experience.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

- HTML5
- CSS
- SCSS/Sass
- JavaScript (ES6)

Libraries + Frameworks

- React
- Node.is
- Nouc.js
- Express
- Redux

Tools + Platforms

- Jira/Confluence
- Slack
- GitVercel
- Drupal 8

RESTful API

Redux

• React Testing Library

- RESTful API
- Heroku

RUTH MATIEU

- ▼ TAMPA, FL
- MATIEU.RUTH@GMAIL.COM
- ⟨813⟩ 528 2976
- WWW.RUTHMATIEU.COM
- **LINKEDIN**
- ⊕ GITHUB

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Development (Student)

LAMBDA SCHOOL - REMOTE | FEB 2020 - PRESENT

- Orchestrate and design efficient large-scale software deployments, including testing features and correcting code.
- Contribute ideas and suggestions in scrum team meetings of up to 7 in order to deliver updates on deadlines, design and enhancements.
- Develop web servers using Node.js and RDBMS, including SQLite and PostgreSQL

Online Drupal Specialist (Jr. Web Developer)

TRAVELOPIA - CLEARWATER, FL | AUG 2019 - PRESENT

- Troubleshoot and debug Drupal CMS issues ensuring visual design and user interface meet industry standards.
- Collaborate with graphic designers, developers, and marketing team to ensure websites are operational.
- Develop, plan and deliver ongoing global e-commerce projects by gathering requirements, organizing resources, training and testing in different web environments and sites.

Insurance Agent

NEW YORK LIFE INSURANCE CO - TAMPA,FL | APR 2018 - JUL 2019

- Assisted in the creation of a new internal search engine to increase employee productivity by 30%.
- Handled approximately 60 inbound sales-related calls per day to qualify individuals interested in purchasing insurance coverage.
- Reviewed policy applications for errors and liaised with underwriters to facilitate quick completion of application process.

EDUCATION

Lambda School

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT & COMPUTER SCIENCE